Mss.B.Ow2 Mss.B.Ow2
American Philosophical Society
- Correspondence
  - Letter to [Lady] Mary [Cooper], March 12, 1872; 6x4; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Richmond Park, A.L.S. 3p. (see R.Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 32.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to G[eorge] R[obert] Gray, April 12, 1872; 7-¼x4-½; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. Asks for his genera, "included by Alph. Milne Edwards in his families" for four animals. Previously cataloged as "B Ow2.21"
  - Letter to Gwyn Jeffreys, July 20, 1873; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Note to Miss Poyser, April 12, July 15, 1873; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.N.S. 1p. (see R.Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 9.) Acknowledgment of her help in his lectures. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to [James] Paget, Dec. 18, 1873; 7 x 4 1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    London, ALS 4p. Discusses plans to move to warmer climate, comments on Paget's illness, gives regards to Lady Paget. Has sent copy of "Hospi Reports" to Langtham.
  - Letter to "My dear Sir", June 11, 1874; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Sir R. Owen papers. Letters to various persons, no. 11.) Concerning fossils. Formerly B Ow2.2
  - Letter to Mrs. [Samuel Pickworth?] Woodward, Oct. 8, 1874; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir R. Owen papers. Letters to various persons, no. 12.) Friendly letter. Formerly B Ow2.2
  - Letter to Mr. Collingwood, Nov. 11, 1874; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to Mrs. Rogers, May 13, 1875; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to Mr. Allingham, July 5, 1875; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to W[illiam Henry] Flower, July 31, 1875; 7 1/4 x 4 1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    British Museum, ALS 2p. Omitted to send to British Museum originals of fossil casts; asks that Flower give them to bearer of letter.
  - Letter to Messrs. Williams & Norgate, April 10, 1876; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter in Italian to unknown., Jan. 29, 1877
  - Letter to R[ichard] H[engist] Horne, Feb. 14, 1877; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to [Richard] Owen, Feb. 19, 1877; Paget, James, Sir, 1814-1899
  - Letter to [Edward William?] Cooke, May 16, 1877; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 2p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 33.) Friendly letter. Refers to the Geological society. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to "My dear Ellen;", June 9, 1877; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 3p. Tells her that Sussex is good for her and he will come as soon as he can leave London.
  - Letter to [President of the British Museum?], June 14, 1877; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Sir Richard Owen Papers.) Delighted with his steps for recovering natural history specimens which were shipped out of the country. Formerly B Ow2.6
  - Letter to [Peter Martin] Duncan, July 6, 1877; 7 1/4" x 4 1/2"; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 3p. Claims of the National museum of natural history to certain collections of natural history. Formerly B Ow2.3
  - Letter to Mr. Grev. Pennell, Nov. 2, 1877; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to Prof. Rich[ard] Owen, Nov. 26, 1877; Holding, Robert E.
  - Letter to Prof. Owen, Dec. 7, 1877; Mivart, St. George Jackson, 1827-1900
  - Letter to "My dear Cooke", May 25, 1878; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to "My dear Neighbour", June 1, 1878; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 2p.,end. (see Sir R.Owen. papers. Letters to various persons, no. 13.) Friendly letter. Formerly B Ow2.2
  - Letter to William White Cooper, Aug. 30, 1878; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 4p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 34.) Friendly letter. Concerning natural history and extinct birds. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to Prof. Owen, Oct. 14, 1878; Müller, F. Max -- (Friedrich Max), -- 1823-1900. -- Science of language.
  - Letter to William White Cooper, Dec. 25, 1878; 6x4; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Richmond park, A.L.S. 3p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 35.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to William White Cooper, Jan. 1, 1879; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Richmond Park, A.L.S. 2p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 36.) Friendly letter. Refers to the Geological society. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to [Henri] Milne-Edwards, Jan. 2, 1879; 6x4; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 2p.,end. (see Owen papers.) Thanks for, and praises, his work on "Physiologie". Formerly B Ow2.8
  - Letter to [Lady] Mary [Cooper], April 16, 1879; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 37.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to "My dear Cooke", May 14, 1879; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to ----, Jan. 16, 1880; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 3p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 38.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to [Henri] Milne-Edwards, April 14, 1880; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 4p.,end. (see Owen papers.) Concerning the archeopteryx. Friendly letter. Formerly B Ow2.8
  - Letter to [Lady] Mary [Cooper], May 15, 1880; 6x4; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Richmond Park, A.L.S. 1p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 39.) Cannot meet her as she wishes. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to William White Cooper, May 19, 1880; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 40.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to H. Charlton Bastian, June 6, 1880; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to [Henri] Milne-Edwards, July 7, 1880; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 3p.,end. (see Owen papers.) Regrets he could not show them through the new wing of the British museum. Believes his work very valuable, and praises it highly. Formerly B Ow2.8
  - Letter to Prof. Owen, Dec. 29, 1880; Murray, T. Douglas
  - Letter to William Holman Hunt, Dec. 30, 1880; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to "My dear Murray", Dec. 30, 1880; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to William Holman Hunt, January 6, 1881; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to Marion Edith Waugh Holman Hunt, January 27, 1881; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to Sir Walter Elliot, Feb. 10, 1881; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Owen papers.) Will try to help William Grant get the position in the British Museum. Formerly B Ow2.17
  - Letter to [John] Greville Fennell, February 11, 1881; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to [Richard] Owen, March 3, 1881; Judd, John W., (John Wesley), 1840-1916
  - Letter to William Holman Hunt, March 28, 1881; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to William Holman Hunt, April 4, 1881; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to Marion Edith Waugh Holman Hunt, April 5, 1881; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Du Chaillu, Paul B[elloni] to Marion Edith Waugh Holman Hunt, April 13, 1881; DuChaillu, Paul Belloni, 1838-1903
  - Letter to Marion Edith Waugh Holman Hunt, May 14, 1881; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to Marion Edith Waugh Holman Hunt, June 23, 1881; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Noted 9/24/10 - signature has been cut out. rshuman 6/28/11.
  - Letter to William Holman Hunt, August 3, 1881; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to R[ichard] H[engist] Horne, Nov. 8, 1881; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to Mrs. Hale, Jan. 11, 1882; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 2p. Works mostly at the Natural History Museum. Thinks St.George Mivart may wish a Cuvier letter and Sketch.
    See: (Sir Richard Owen Papers.)
  - Letter to "Dear Sir", Feb. 25, 1882; 7x4½; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. Work prevents Owen from visiting his correspondent's "grand & varied & instructive Country." Refers to the British Museum and its national collections of natural history.
  - Letter to William White Cooper, April 6, 1882; 6x4; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Richmond Park, A.L.S. 4p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 42.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to William White Cooper, April 20, 1882; 3x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. on postcard. 1p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons no. 58.) Thanks for catalogue. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to R[ichard] H[engist] Horne, May 25, 1882; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to William White Cooper, July 8, 1882; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Richmond Park, A.L.S. 2p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 43.) Concerning birds. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to "My dear Friend" [William White Cooper?], July 20, 1882; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Richmond Park, A.L.S. 2p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 44.) Friendly letter. Concerning birds. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to Marion Edith Waugh Holman Hunt, Sept. 2, 1882; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to "Dear Emily", Oct. 25, 1882; 6x4; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Richmond Park, A.L.S. 3p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 45.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to [Lady] Mary [Cooper], Jan. 6, 1883; 6x4; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Richmond Park, A.L.S. 3p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 46.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to Marion Edith Waugh Holman Hunt, July 10, 1883; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to Marion Edith Waugh Holman Hunt, July 14, 1883; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to R[ichard] H[engist] Horne, August 11, 1883; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to "My dear Friend" [Cooper], Dec. 29, 1883; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to "Rev. & dear Sir", Feb. 19, 1884; 6x4; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p.and photograph. (see Sir.R. Owen papers. Letters to various persons, no. 14.) Friendly letter. Formerly B Ow2.2
  - Letter to William White Cooper, March 16, 1884; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Richmond Park, A.L.S. 1p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 47.) Friendly letter. Refers to the Geological society. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to William White Cooper, June 14, 1884; 6x4; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Richmond Park, A.L.S. 2p. (see R.Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 48.) Concerning bird skeletons. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to "My dear Friend" [William White Cooper?], July 19, 1884; 6-1/2x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 2p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 49.) Thanks for the gift. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to "My dear Mary", July 21, 1884; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to [Lady] Mary [Cooper], Dec. 1, 1884; 6x4; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Richmond Park, A.L.S. 3p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 50.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to William Holman Hunt, Dec. 6, 1884; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to William White Cooper, Feb. 2, 1885; 6x4; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Richmond Park, A.L.S. 4p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 51.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to Marion Edith Waugh Holman Hunt, Feb. 26, 1885; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to Marion Edith Waugh Holman Hunt, June 20, 1885; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to H[enry] Cholmondely-Pennell, Oct. 16, 1886; 6x4; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Richmond Park, A.L.S. 2p. (see R. Owen. Letters to Various persons, no. 52.) Congratulates him on his book of English fishes. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to "My dear Robinson", Nov. 3, 1886
  - Letter to H[enry] Cholmondely-Pennell, Nov. 19, 1886; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to "My very dear Friend" [William White Cooper?], April 2, 1887; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Richmond Park, A.L.S. 1p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 53.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to Woodhouse Braine, June 4, 1887; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. Cannot be Steward at the annual dinner of the Fellows of the Royal College of Surgeons.
  - Letter to Richard Owen, Dec. 1, 1887; Marr, J. E. (John Edward), 1857-1933
  - Letter to Lady [Mary] Cooper, Dec. 26, 1887; 8x5; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Richmond Park, A.L.S. 1p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 54.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to the Master and Wardens of the Salters Company, January 19, 1888; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to Richard Owen, Dec. 1, 1888; 6x4; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Richmond Park, A.L.S. 4p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 55.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to Lady [Mary] Cooper, April 12, 1889; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Richmond Park, A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 56.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to Marion Edith Waugh Holman Hunt, June 24, 1889; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Letter to ----., undated; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 3p. January 20[?].
  - Letter to Sir John Lubbock, undated; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. March 6.
  - Letter to Richard Owen, Undated; 7 1/4 x 4 3/4; Clark, James, Sir, 1788-1870
    Monday, n.y. A.L. 1p. Arranges time and place for Owen to give lecture. 20th April.
  - Letter to Richard Owen, undated; Hawkins, Caesar H.
    A.L.S. 1p. April 29.
  - Letter to Marion Edith Waugh Holman Hunt, undated; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 2p. April 29.
  - Letter to ----., undated; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 2p. June 2.
  - Letter to Mrs. E[lizabeth] Evans, Undated; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Richmond Park, A.L.S. 3p. July 1. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 60.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to Prof. Owen, undated; Jones, Bence, 1814-1873
    A.L.S. 2p. July 8.
  - Letter to William Fothergill Cooke, undated; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. July 14.
  - Letter to Mr. Bather, Undated; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. July 20. Pasted on back in printed advertisement of Owen's works. (see Sir R.Owen papers. Letters to various persons, no. 16.) Friendly letter. Refers to the Zoological society and the ant-eater. Formerly B Ow2.2
  - Letter to Mr. Ward, undated; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. July 29.
  - Letter to Lady [Mary] Cooper, Undated; 6x4; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. August 14. (see R.Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 61.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to "My dear Cooke", undated; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. September 5.
  - Letter to Richard Owen, undated; Chadwick, Edwin, 1800-1890
    A.L.S. 1p. November 1. Note "47 w m".
  - Letter to Richard Owen, undated; Sedgwick, Adam, 1785-1873
    A.L.S. 2p. November 10.
  - Letter to Richard Owen, undated; Brodie, Benjamin, Sir, 1783-1862
    A.L.S. 1p. December 10. Note "58 w m".
  - Autograph., Undated; 2x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.D.S. 1p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 70.) Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to Edward Parker Charlesworth, Undated; 9x7-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Saturday. A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir. R. Owen papers. Letters to various persons, no. 21.) Concerning mollusks. Formerly B Ow2.2
  - Letter to William White Cooper, Undated; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 67.) Introduces F. Dalton. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to William White Cooper, Undated; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Sunday morning. A.L.S. 1p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 62.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to William White Cooper, Undated; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Sunday Evening. A.L.S. 2p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 63.) Recommends a patient. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to William White Cooper, Undated; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Wednesday. A.L.S. 1p.and end. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 64.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to William White Cooper, Undated; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Friday. A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 65.) Friendly letter. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to [Lady] Mary [Cooper], Undated; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Saturday morning. A.L.S. 2p. (see R. Owen. Letters to Various persons, no. 66.) Invitation to dinner. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to "My dear Cooper", undated; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. Saturday.
  - Letter to [Henry?] Curling, Undated; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 2p. (see R. Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 68.) Illness of Robert Clift. Originally B Ow2.1
  - Letter to [Hepworth?] Dixon, Undated; 6x4; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 2p.and end. (see Sir. R.Owen papers. Letters to various persons, no. 22.) Friendly letter. Formerly B Ow2.2
  - Letter to Eliza, Undated; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Friday. A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to Mrs. Fitch, Undated; Sedgwick, Adam, 1785-1873
    Museum, Monday. morning. A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Sir R.Owen papers. Letters to various persons, no. 17.) Will introduce R. Owen and see fossils. Formerly B Ow2.2
  - Letter to Mrs. Fowler, Undated; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Friday. A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir R. Owen papers. Letters to various persons, no. 20.) Friendly letter. Formerly B Ow2.2
  - Letter to Richard Owen, undated; Buckland, Francis T., (Francis Trevelyan), 1826-1880
    A.L.S. 3p. Sunday.
  - Letter to Thomas Spring-Rice, Baron, Monteagle of Brandon, Undated; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Tuesday evening. A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir R. Owen papers. Letters to various persons, no. 18.) Refuses invitation. Formerly B Ow2.2
  - Letter to "My dear Lord" [Thomas Spring-Rice?, Baron, Monteagle of Brandon], Undated; 7x4-1/2; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    Thursday evening. A.L.S. 1p. (see Sir R. Owen papers. Letters to various persons, no. 19.) Accepts invitation. Formerly B Ow2.2
  - Letter to "Your Grace", undated; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    A.L.S. 1p. Formerly in Ow2.24. Note on reverse reads 'Gloufagh or Cloufagh (supplies Lancaster with water)'.
  - Fragment of Paper on Dinosaurs, undated; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
  - Memoir on the Dinornis, portion of manuscript, Undated; 10x8; Owen, Richard, 1804-1892
    addressed to Dr. Fraser. A.D.S. 1p. With this is an autograph of Owen, dated Nov.1,1865. Formerly B Ow2.4
  - Passes to the gardens of the Zoological Society of London., Undated; 3x4-1/2; Zoological Society of London
    by order of R[ichar]d Owen. D.S. 7 items. (see R.Owen. Letters to various persons, no. 69.) Originally B Ow2.1